# Gustavo Andrés Marin

## **SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER**



#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Online version

Nationality:	Italian / Argentinian
City:	Madrid, Spain
Phone:	(+34) 658 817 219
Email:	gustavoandresmarin@gmail.com

#### **PROFESIONAL PROFILE**

I am a developer with over 10 years of experience in web application development. I've been working throughout those years with technologies like PHP, MySQL, Oracle, Javascript; and with lots of libraries and frameworks like jQuery, Backbone, ExtJS, Zend Framework.

I studied computer science at Universidad Tecnologica de Rosario, despite I did not get graduated, that provides me a solid theorical background which suits perfectly with my working experience. I am a passionate and enthusiastic developer with significant proficiency in PHP, MySQL and Javascript, quite active and self-taught.

I am currently focused on improving my server side javascript and NoSQL skills.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

BACKEND

PHP & MySQL	Expert
JSON, XML, REST	Expert
LAMPP, RabbitMQ	Moderate
Zend, Smarty	Moderate
Simfony	Basic
MongoDB, NodeJS	Basic

### FRONT-END FRAMEWORKS & TOOLS

Javascript, AJAX	Expert
jQuery, Lo-Dash	Expert
GruntJS, JSHint	Expert
HTML5 APIs	Moderate
Backbone, ExtJS	Moderate
CSS3, AngularJS	Basic

#### **EDITORS & IDES**

#### OTHER TOOLS

Vim	Expert	Linux & Bash scripts	Expert
Eclipse, Netbeans	Moderate	Git, GitHub, SVN	Moderate
SublimeText, WebStorm		Amazon AWS	Basic

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Analyst & Developer**

Mar 2007 - PRESENT

PRISA DIGITAL

Spain's leading company in production of digital news and information. One of my firsts task here was to improve the backend made with PHP and ExtJS. Also have helped design and develop new funcionalities to the company's propietary framework, both Javascript and PHP parts.

In 2009 I've worked as **Project Manager** in the complete redesing and refactoring of **cuatro.com**, leading, deciding and coordinating efforts of a group of ten developers.

In 2010 worked in design and development of the **VOD platform**'s security layer used by the previous **Canal+** video on demand feeds.

In 2012 was assigned to the **Push Notification project**. A cloud system to create, manage and deliver messages to several of the company apps. Involving innovatives technologies as **Amazon WS, RabbitMQ** and cloud cluster management.

Since the beginning of 2013 I'm involved in the development of YOMVI Web, **Live Streaming and VOD platform of Canal+**.

- keywords: javascript, jquery, ajax, xml, mysql, php, pear, zend
- Sites: yomvi.es, cuatro.com, elpais.com

## **Analyst & Developer**

May 2002 - Jul 2006

### FIAT AUTO ESPAÑA

International automotive group. In this company I was involved in FIAT's Link intranet on all phases of development from analysis through design, coding, testing, and implementation. This intranet application consisted of showroom sale, logistics control, stock control, sales & productivity reports and CRM. This was used by the dealer network in Spain. I worked on the early stages of a later migration to the rest of Europe market.

Also worked in design and development stages of aftersale and workshops application to control and benchmark car reparation processes. And developed several automated webservices to update the website with car and accessories data on the internet.

- keywords: php, oracle, pl/sql, xml, soap, javascript, xhtml, ajax
- Sites: fiat.es

**Senior Developer** 

Oct 2000 - Jan 2002

Claxson Interactive

Multimedia company, entertainment content provider worldwide. In this company I worked as senior PHP developer. Involved in code migration from ASP to PHP and from MySQL to Oracle and PL/SQL. Also been involved in development of backend for content administration and a multilangual/multiplatform forum application.

- keywords: php, mysql, oracle, pl/sql, zope, xml, javascript
- Sites: elsitio.com.ar, muchmusic.com.ar, venus.com.ar, infinito.com.ar

**Junior Developer** 

Jun 2000 - Oct 2000

PowerSite Argentina

Web sites development company. In this company I worked as programmer in several customer web sites, doing coding tasks, sql procedures, and propietary framework development in php.

- keywords: html, javascript, php, mysql, postgresql
- Sites: powersite.com.ar, cirugiasestetica.com, medintersa.com.ar

## **Developer / Sys Admin**

Feb 1999 - May 2000

Zarcrom Argentina

World renown web hosting company. In this company I worked as server administrator and technical support to our customers, performing administration tasks of Apache on Cobalt RAQ servers, new sites configuration, user and sites management, DNS configuration. Also performing as a webmaster for several of our customers and the company's main site in Argentina.

- keywords: html, php, mysql, apache, linux, ssh
- Sites: www.zarcrom.com.ar

### **EDUCATION**

## Ingeniería en Sistemas de Información

1995 - 1999

Universidad Tecnológica Nacional

### Bachiller Técnico. Nivel Secundario.

1990 - 1994

Instituto Politécnico Superior

### **COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION**

## **GNU/Linux LPIC-1 Certification**

2006

Instituto Novatech Madrid

This course includes: work at the Linux command line, maintenance tasks, backup & restore, install and configure a workstation, connect it to a LAN, printing, samba.

# **English technical translation**

1994

Instituto Politécnico Superior